the forest are like home to me.
Je me sens chez moi dans la forêt.
You know, it's somewhere I can just go to sit
C'est un endroit où je peux aller me poser
and think
et réfléchir.
it helps relieve a lot of stress.
Ça m'aide à évacuer le stress.
I've always kind of struggled with breathing
J'ai toujours eu du mal à respirer
and it's gotten worse. You know, I thought I had asthma at first, but I didn't.
mais ça a empiré. Au début on pensais que c'étais de l'asthme.
So I just went in
Je suis allé à l'hôpital
and
et...
you know, they said that I had a tumor that was cancerous.
on m'a dis que j'avais une tumeur cancéreuse.
I want to say I was 22 or 23.
Je crois que j'avais 22 ou 23 ans,
So
donc...
obviously that's pretty young to be diagnosed or something like that.
évidemment la plupart des jeunes n'ont pas ce genre de diagnostique.
It changed a lot of stuff for me,
Ça a changé beaucoup de choses pour moi.
A lot of people in my family have cancer.
Beaucoup dans ma famille ont eu des cancers.
I'm going through the same radiologist that my grandma went through.
Je vois le même radiologiste qu'a vu ma grand-mère.
I went through a couple rounds of chemotherapy
J'ai eu plusieurs chimiothérapies
and I was pretty much told it's not working,
qui ne marchait pas, à ce qu'on me disait.
we're gonna have to
On va devoir
either take you in for surgery within this week or you're not gonna make it.
vous opérer cette semaine, ou vous ne survivrez pas.
So that was like,
Donc,
my first life expectancy that I was given was either
le premier ultimatum qu'on m'a donné était
do the surgery or die within a couple of weeks.
fait l'opération ou meurt dans quelques semaines.
So I had the surgery,
Alors j'ai fait l'opération.
there's no cancer in my lungs anymore.
Je n'ai plus de cancer des poumons
But before I had the surgery, it had spread.
mais en attendant l'opération, il s'est répandu.
So
Alors
today I haven't really
en ce moment je ne fait plus
done much chemo mainly because of health care.
de chimio, parce que je n'ai pas d'assurance.
I lost my health care when I switched jobs and I haven't gotten any since
Je l'ai perdu quand j'ai changé de travail, et je n'en ai plus depuis.
when I got that diagnosis, I was at a very low point in my life.
Quand on m'a diagnostiqué ma vie n'allais déjà pas bien
It wasn't like, oh, wow, I need to change this. It was like, oh, wow, I can finally die.
Je ne me suis pas dis que je devais me battre, je me suis dis « Je peux enfin mourir. »
It was my friends that really brought me back.
Mes ami.e.s en ont décidé autrement.
I reached out into the fandom and I made my friend major.
J'ai rejoins le fandom Furry et rencontré mon ami Major.
It's just fun to meet new people and that's really what I want to do in the fandom.
C'est sympa de rencontrer de nouvelles personnes et c'est ce que je voulais faire.
I think we all have those moments in the fandom where we contemplate leaving it.
Je pense qu'on tous ces moments où on s'imagine quitter cette communauté.
I've had that moment when I got that diagnosis,
C'étais mon cas après qu'on m'ai diagnostiqué.
is this really doing anything for my life other than costing me money to get art.
Est-ce que ça m'aide vraiment ? Au delà de ce que je paye pour les dessins.
But the answer was, yes, it was doing something for my life.
Et la réponse est : oui, ça me change la vie.
I'm so nervous about presenting this right now.
Je suis tellement nerveux à l'idée de l'ouvrir.
I'm always in here.
Qu'est ce qu'on a là ?
I'm shaking. I'm like shaking.
Je tremble, je tremble...
seeing the way that suits kind of change people and the way that suits
Voir à quel point les gens se transforment quand ils portent une fursuit et à quel point
can bring other people joy is kind of what made me want one.
ça apporte de la joie aux autres, m'a donné envie d'en avoir une.
I can put a smile on someone's face and not
Je peux apporter de la joie à quelqu'un sans prendre
risk losing my job for not being a straight male
le risque de perdre mon travail à cause de mon orientation.
So this is like a partially painted head, but this is his head
Tout les motifs ne sont pas finis, mais voila sa tête.
getting into first suiting making a fruit suits was,
Me lancer dans le fursuiting et créer des fursuits
it was kind of a random thing that I actually got into it.
a été quelque chose d'assez inattendu.
Uh prior to doing this,
Avant de faire ça
I had my own printing business that I've known for a lot of years
j'avais ma propre entreprise d'impression depuis des années.
when I received a city that was made by cyber.
Quand j'ai reçu Acai, qui a été faite par Cyber.
That was an incredibly special thing to me.
C'étais un moment incroyablement spécial pour moi.
It really, really impacted me in so many ways and it completely transformed my life
Ça m'a vraiment impacté à plein de niveaux et a transformé ma vie.
and I wanted to be a part of that create
Je voulais participer à tout ça, concevoir
these things that bring such joy and happiness to everybody.
ces créatures qui apportent tant de joie et de bonheur à tout le monde.
I sold my previous business that gave me the capital to start this up.
J'ai revendu mon entreprise, ce qui m'a donné le capital pour me lancer.
Every suit that I do is slightly different.
Chaque fursuit que je fait est un peu différente,
I'm always looking at, how can I improve it? How can I make it better?
j'essaye de toujours trouver des moyens de les améliorer.
Oh, don't do that.
Oh ne fait pas ça !
So the suit that we're working on is hero,
En ce moment on travaille sur la fursuit de Hero.
everything seemed normal business as usual.
À la base tout se déroulais comme d'habitude
Then out of the blue, I had a couple of people that poked me.
et puis plusieurs clients m'ont contacté et ont demandé :
It's like, hey, we'd like for you to put heroes commission in front of ours.
Est-ce qu'il serait possible de faire passé Hero en priorité ?
So I didn't know any story on, I had no knowledge of what it was but upon, you know,
Je ne savais pas trop ce qu'il se passait, je n'étais pas au courant, mais en demandant
kind of poking these people and getting more information
plus d'informations à mes clients et
and learning of his story is just like,
en apprenant son histoire, je me dis :
oh my gosh, he needs to have that suit much sooner.
Oh mon dieu, il lui faut sa fursuit le plus tôt possible.
So I use a piece of software
J'utilise ce logiciel où
where this is not him.
(ce n'est pas lui)
I'll take the measurements and I can basically
je prend les mesures du corps et
plug those measurements into the software to go ahead
je les rentre dans le logiciel pour qu'il crée
and create all of the lines that we're gonna need on this to create the pattern.
toutes les découpes dont on aura besoin pour créer son motif.
The software then largely converts it over here to the two dimensional side.
Le logiciel les convertis ensuite en patron, juste ici,
Then I will output this pattern. I'll print this pattern out.
que j'enregistre et que je découpe.
Most vinyl cutters just only cut the vinyl.
La plupart des découpeuses vinyle ne coupe que ça.
This machine is actually cutting the vinyl and the paper so we can be able to pull
Cette machine peut couper le vinyle et le papier, alors on peut prendre
those pieces out and then Tetris them on the
ces pièces et les assembler sur la fourrure
food to get the best utilization of the foot
et éviter d'avoir trop de chutes.
because otherwise trying to figure that out, it's just too much brain damage.
Sans ça c'est c'est un coup à se faire des noeuds au cerveau.
This is just easier
C'est beaucoup plus simple.
and see this is going to be
Voyons, ici ça sera
black luxury shag
de la Luxury Shag noire
and this piece down here, this is going to be white arctic fox, laugh,
et ce morceau là sera de là White Artic Fox. W.A.F. !
this is going to be gray, arctic fox.
Celle-là de la Gray Arctic Fox.
Typical turnaround from the time that I start the suit until the
Le temps entre le moment où je commence la fursuit
suit is done is usually in the neighborhood of about two months.
et où je la finie est d'environ deux mois.
I definitely put this suit on the express path simply because
Cette fursuit j'essaye de la terminer vite parce que
the biggest thing he's fighting is time, it's, you know, the unknown.
son principal problème c'est le temps qu'il lui reste, c'est l'inconnu.
I worry about if he's gonna like the suit,
J'espère vraiment qu'il aimera la fursuit,
you're creating something that is this person's idea of who they are.
vous donnez forme à l'idée qu'une personne se fait d'elle même.
Am I actually doing that? Am I, am I able to to achieve what he was hoping that
Est-ce que je le fais bien ? Est-ce que je suis capable de faire la
he's actually coming out here next monday as a
Il passera nous voir lundi prochain,
matter of fact to take delivery of the suit?
pour récupérer la fursuit.
Uh this is something I normally don't do.
Ce n'est pas quelque chose que je fais d'habitude,
It's kind of a little bit, you know, it's a bit of an unprecedented situation.
mais vous savez, la situation est particulière.
We're gonna have this thing done by monday and it's kind of all hands on deck,
Tout le monde est sur le pont jusqu'à lundi prochain, pour
getting the suit complete.
finir cette fursuit.
I was working a corporate job that I really did not like and
Je n'aimais pas mon travail dans une grande entreprise,
my sister saw an ad on next door that was like costume maker,
ma soeur a vu une annonce locale : Créateur de costume
somebody with so many experience preferred, which have a seamstress.
recherche quelqu'un avec une expérience en couture. Je suis couturière.
So I came thinking that it was probably for,
Je suis me suis dis qu'il devait y avoir un petit
there's like a little theater in the town here.
théâtre dans le coin
So I thought I would be like making costumes for the theater.
et que je devrais faire des costumes de théâtre.
And then I come to the interview and Ryan's like, what do you know about Ferraris?
J'arrive à l'entretien et Ryan me demande : que savez-vous des Furries ?
Didn't know that much. Now I know much more.
Je ne connaissais pas, maintenant j'en sais beaucoup plus.
I know a lot more work goes into it than I would have previously thought
Je sais que ça demande beaucoup plus de travail que ce que j'imaginais.
to the firm
Allons aux fourrures
and I bring this,
et j'ai besoin de ça.
could be this.
Peut-être celle-là...
I didn't know this business existed.
Je ne savais pas que ça existait
I didn't know that there was an industry for this.
ou qu'il y avais une industrie pour ça.
We were doing a family walk with our daughter and the
Pendant une balade en famille avec
dogs one day and Ryan was outside and he says,
ma fille et mon chien, Ryan était dehors et il me demande :
are you looking for work?
Tu cherches du travail ?
And I said, yes. And so he said, would you like to work at wagon?
J'ai répondu Oui ! Il me demande si je veux travailler à Waggery.
And I said, what's Magarri
Je lui demande ce qu'est Waggery.
I interviewed with him and he told me all about the business and I started working.
J'ai passé un entretien avec lui, il m'a tout expliqué et je me suis lancé.
What I love the most is when all the heads are in
Ce que je préfère c'est quand les têtes sont ici
here and I can try them on when I'm working and stuff.
et quand je peux les essayer pendant le boulot.
But I love when all the heads are in here because you kind of make that
Non, j'adore quand elle sont là parce qu'on fait
connection with the body because a lot of times there's just bodies and no heads.
cette connexion avec le reste du corps, la plupart du temps il y a juste un corps et pas de tête.
So it's really neat when you can kind of get a feel for the character of that person.
Donc c'est vraiment sympa d'avoir une meilleur idée du personnage de cette personne.
There's so many projects going at one time typically that trying
On a tellement de commandes en même, ça peut
to keep each project straight in your head is often difficult.
être parfois un peu difficile de se concentrer.
I would say this is probably like the fourth
Je dirais que c'est la quatrième
most complex suit I've done since I've been here,
fursuit la plus compliquée depuis que j'ai commencé.
Maybe 150-200 pieces
Entre 100 et 200 pièces
just for the body. Then the head is a lot of smaller pieces too.
juste pour le corps. La tête c'est plein de petits morceaux.
We were, I was looking at
Je regardais
the map out of the body with Corey and trying
le schéma du corps avec Corey et on se demandais
to figure out are these random pieces or do these,
si ces morceaux allaient vraiment quelque part.
I think these are those triangles that we did off the back for the foot, pause,
Je crois que c'est les triangles sous les pattes arrières.
what I'm seeing on the pattern does not match what I'm seeing.
Ce qu'il y a sur le schéma ne correspond pas à ce que je vois là.
Let's see here,
Laisse moi regarder.
this is this one here.
Celui là va là.
This one goes in here and this one goes here and this goes in here,
Celui-là va ici, celui-là ici là et l'autre ici.
let's see here. What is that? So these are
Voyons, qu'est ce que c'est ? Celui-là
this top one that that's definitely,
c'est celui au dessus, c'est sûr.
yeah, that one is definitely not right.
Par contre celui-là n'est pas bon.
So we got some pieces that are missing for this project
Bon, on a perdu quelques morceaux de fourrure
and
et...
if they don't get put in the right place, then it's a problem.
si on ne les met pas aux bons endroits, on aura un problème.
Everybody looking all around for something.
Donc on les cherche partout.
Here we go, No, that's not it. Part of fighting cancer is having support,
Et voilà ! Ah non c'est pas ça...
You need a support network and feeling like nobody wanted me,
Il vous faut un groupe pour vous aider. Alors avoir l'impression que personne ne voulait de moi...
it was just impossible.
était impossible à supporter.
I pretty much just lost everything. I stopped doing chemo.
J'ai tout perdu. J'ai arrêté la chimio.
I stopped caring, my job performance went to ship.
Je m'en fichais, mes performances au travail se sont effondrées.
I gave up
J'ai abandonné...
and then there was the whole thing with my grandma when she got diagnosed,
Après il y a eu tout ce truc quand ma grand-mère a été diagnostiqué,
she's the only one that I ever told about it that I had it.
c'étais la seule à savoir pour mon cancer,
I remember her saying, you know, I don't want to bury my grandson.
Je me souviens qu'elle a dis : Je ne veux pas enterrer mon petit fils.
You know I'm only 22,, she's 70
Après tout, je n'avais que 22 ans, elle 70.
and she just cried and
Elle a pleuré,
that just kind of left me.
alors je me suis senti...
You know,
On se sent comme une merde quand on abandonne sa
on your whole life and you're gonna hurt all these people around you.
propre vie et qu'on réalise qu'on va blesser ceux qui nous aime.
She had colon cancer
Elle avait un cancer du colon.
radiologist had told her she was in remission so she had beat it
Les radiologues lui ont dis qu'elle était en rémission, qu'elle avait réussi.
and then she went back and they said yeah you're stage four,
Mais le cancer est revenu, au stade terminal.
you're gonna be you have five months at the most.
Vous avez au maximum 5 mois à vivre.
And she died like a week later
Elle est morte une semaine plus tard.
she wanted to meet my friend major because I told her a lot about him and he
Je voulais qu'elle rencontre mon ami Major, parce que je n'arrêtais pas de lui en parler.
agreed to fly up and then she ended up passing a couple of days before he came
Il était d'accord pour venir, mais elle morte deux jours avant son arrivé.
instead of canceling.
Au lieu d'annuler le vol
He flew all the way from florida to salt lake to come to her funeral with me.
il a pris l'avion depuis la Floride jusqu'à Salt Lake City pour venir à l'enterrement avec moi.
Her passing is literally the hardest I've ever cried in
Je n'avais jamais autant pleuré de ma vie
my life and my best friend had to see it.
et mon meilleur ami a tout vu.
But to me that prove he was in it for the long haul and that he was just irreplaceable.
Ça m'a prouvé qu'il serait toujours là sur le long terme et qu'il était irremplaçable.
And I've never had friendships like that outside of this fandom.
Je n'ai jamais eu d'amitié comme ça en dehors des furries.
You know internet friendships can be real friendships,
Vous savez les amitiés sur Internet sont de vrais amitiés.
We use this room for doing the 3D.
Cette pièce c'est pour l'impression 3D,
Printing all of the mold, pouring all the resin work that we do just for claws
le remplissage des moules et pour les griffes qu'on fait en résine.
and we do all the airbrushing.
Ainsi que la peinture au pistolet.
We basically used this room to get away from the for for and
En gros, cette pièce est là pour resté à l'écart de la fourrure.
three d printers don't mix well for and resin molds don't mix well.
La fourrure ne fait pas bon ménage avec la résine et les imprimantes 3D.
So this effectively kind of becomes our
C'est un peu devenu notre clean room.
but we have this set up and then we also have a third machine over here
On a tout ça qui est en place et on a aussi une autre imprimante juste ici
and this machine just got finished putting these
qui viens juste de finir d'imprimer ça.
so these are completed set of teeth and I,
Un set de dents complet et d'yeux.
so what we do is go in here and clean off all the,
Il faut juste le prendre et enlever
the goobers
tout le surplus
and remove all of the support material.
et enlever tout les supports.
A few little goobers to fix but
Un peu de surplus à enlever mais
overall pretty good
c'est plutôt pas mal.
here at Wagah re costumes. I am in charge of building the heads
Chez Waggery, je suis responsable de la construction des têtes
and just about everything that is involved with that.
et tout ce qui va autour.
I've always been a painter drawer sculptor out of school.
J'ai toujours été peintre et sculpteur, en sortant de l'école
I've dove right into the gallery business and got to learn a lot about fine art,
je me suis intéressé directement aux galeries d'arts et j'ai beaucoup appris sur l'art.
started my own business providing services for artists,
J'ai lancé mon entreprise de service pour les artistes
galleries and museums basically got burnt out on that
et galeries d'art. J'en ai eu ma claque
and I was desperate to find something unique.
et je voulais vraiment trouver quelque chose différent.
That's how I met Ryan
C'est comme ça que j'ai rencontré Ryan.
came for an interview and he explained furry to me
J'ai fait un entretien et il m'a expliqué les furries
and
et
I started the next day.
j'ai commencé dès le lendemain.
My kids knew what it was.
Mes enfants connaissaient,
They were surprised that I wanted to do this.
ils étaient un peu surprise que je veuille faire ça.
I kind of just like the sheer playfulness of it.
J'aime bien le coté ludique de tout ça,
It kind of seems like a
ça me semble être
a nice way to just to get out of yourself.
une bonne façon de s'échapper.
People who might be extremely shy or might have some social anxieties.
Pour les gens qui sont très timide ou très anxieux socialement.
It's kind of a tool for dealing with that. It's really interesting
C'est un outil pour combattre ça, c'est très intéressant.
flocking is something that's been around for a very, very long time.
Le flocage est une technique qui existe depuis longtemps,
Typically where you see it is like an in car interior looking your center console.
appliqué sur les console central des voitures par exemple.
It's kind of fuzzy lined in there.
La partie un peu douce.
Uh This was just a way for us to be able to create a very matte black look of
Pour nous c'est une façon de créer un noire vraiment très mate
something, but also because their first suits, they want to be fuzzy.
mais aussi parce que pour une fursuit, il faut que ça soit doux.
These will complete out the eye.
Ça ira sur le pourtour des yeux.
Right now. I have 33 d printers. Uh two of these machines are larger.
Là j'ai trois imprimantes 3D, deux d'entre elle sont très grandes,
They're used for doing all of the molds.
on les utilise pour créer les moules.
So because whenever we're needing, we steal this.
Parce que chaque fois qu'on doit... (je peux te piquer ça ?)
I sculpt a positive in the software from that positive,
Je sculpte un positif dans le logiciel, et depuis ce positif
I generate a negative and that's what we print is the negatives.
je génère un négatif qui sera imprimer en 3D.
So that way, these are, these are clamshells
Elles peuvent s'assembler
that comes together.
et former un moule.
We put the foam in here. The head bus goes down, the foam expands into the head bust
On ajoute la mousse, une tête de mannequin et la mousse gonfle autour de la tête.
The phone we're gonna use expands 15 times
La mousse gonflera d'un facteur 15.
Part B is the resin and the part A is really the activator.
Le composant B est la résine, le A est juste l'activateur.
You only have 35 seconds
Vous avez 35 secondes
as soon as they touch each other.
à partir du moment où ils sont mélangés.
Now the foam is expanding and I want to just keep pressure
La mousse gonfle alors je m'assure de mettre un peu de poids
on this
sur la tête.
From the design to the printing to the prep.
Du design, à l'impression jusqu'au moulage
You know, you're, you're talking a good 10 hours
on est bien dans les 10 heures de travail.
and then these, but the molds take,
En plus de ça, les moules prennent
you know, nearly a day and a half to print
presque une journée et demi à imprimer.
if you let it sit too long.
Si on laisse reposer trop longtemps...
the mold can really stick to the foam and then you've got to,
Le mousse va rester attaché au moule et alors
you've got kind of a disaster.
ça devient un vrai désastre.
You know, in half an hour it'll be
D'ici une demi-heure
the tackiness will be gone.
elle ne sera plus aussi poisseuse.
Hero is part of me
Hero fait parti de moi mais
and he is,
il est aussi,
you know me,
moi-même
but at the same time it's what he represents that matters to me.
et, d'un autre coté, c'est ce qu'il représente qui compte vraiment pour moi.
That's hero
C'est Hero.
the name hero comes from a wolf dog at Spring Creek. Wolf dogs
Le nom Hero viens d'un chien-loup de Springcreek Wolfdogs,
working with him gave me a little more hope in life.
travailler en sa compagnie m'a donner un peu d'espoir.
You know, it made me feel like I had a friend when I was in a situation that
Il m'a donné l'impression d'avoir un ami, dans un moment
I didn't know anyone.
où je n'avais personne.
The design for hero is actually from another wolf dog named thatcher.
Le design de Hero vient d'un autre chien loup appelé ???Thatcher???
I just kind of took the color palette from him.
Ma palette de couleurs vient de lui.
Hero is a werewolf. He's a werewolf.
Hero est un loup-garou, un loup-garou...
The inspiration for that came from my childhood living with my dad
J'ai été inspiré par mon enfance, quand je vivais avec mon père.
Ford Duchenne is kind of known as the skin walker ranch.
Fort Duchesne est connu pour le ranch Skinwalker,
There's a lot of reports of UFO sightings and werewolf sightings
où il y a eu beaucoup de témoignages de rencontre avec des O.V.N.I. et des loup-garous
and my dad claimed to study a lot of this stuff.
et mon père était dans l'étude de ce genre de truc.
I hadn't talked to him for a while
Je ne lui avais pas parlé depuis longtemps
and the last time he had heard from me,
et la dernière fois qu'on s'est vu
we got in a fight and I said something like I hate you
on s'est disputé et j'ai dis quelque chose du genre : Je te déteste !
and
Alors...
you know, I've never got to say goodbye.
je n'ai jamais eu l'occasion de dire au-revoir.
that's kind of what made me choose a werewolf is my character.
C'est pour ça que j'ai choisi un loup-garou comme personnage.
That was a way for me to channel some of him
C'étais un moyen pour moi d'avoir un peu de mon père.
and ultimately that's what hero is.
Au final ce qu'est Hero
It's just kind of a combination of people in my life
c'est un mélange de tout les gens dans ma vie,
that you know, change who you are as a person
qui m'ont fait changer en tant qu'individu.
he represents, showing people that you're not alone in the world,
Il représente le fait de montrer qu'on est pas seul au monde,
despite how hard things get, you can't just lose hope.
que malgré les épreuves, il ne faut pas perdre espoir.
We got G. F. That's this one.
Ici, c'est du G.A.F.
This is black mink
Ça c'est couleur vison noir.
Gaff, laugh
G.A.F - W.A.F
when I didn't mark
Un qui n'est pas marqué...
cf.
C.F
See if I can find any white super seal.
Je regarde si j'ai pas du blanc Super-Seal.
Okay, It looks like I have to pull that off the roll
Bon je crois que je vais devoir sortir tout ça.
two bags
Deux sacs !
21st
Trop de fourrures différentes...
with heroes head.
Pour la tête de Hero...
His rough sheets show very snarly or you know mean type
Sa refsheet le montre très hargneux, genre
of wolf type of thing and very intense and he's like,
grand méchant loup, assez extrême, mais il me disais
well, in reality, I don't want to be that, you know, it's like,
qu'en pratique il n'était pas du tout comme ça.
I'm not that person is like my artwork shows that, but you know,
Ce n'est pas comme moi, je sais que c'est ce que montre mes dessins, mais
as far as who I'm going to be in suit, that's not really who I am.
en réalité je ne serais pas comme ça en fursuit.
So, it's one of those scenarios of where it's like, okay, well,
So, it's one of those scenarios of where it's like, okay, well,
given what his character is,
given what his character is,
whether it's the suit that I'm doing here for
whether it's the suit that I'm doing here for
hero or pretty much any suit that we make.
hero or pretty much any suit that we make.
The head is really kind of the key piece
The head is really kind of the key piece
is what gives the suit of Soul
is what gives the suit of Soul
two down.
two down.
Who knows how many more to go.
Who knows how many more to go.
This is the tedious part of doing this, but
This is the tedious part of doing this, but
the time is not spent to do it right.
the time is not spent to do it right.
The end result does not come out very good.
The end result does not come out very good.
I am
I am
just trying to match up what
just trying to match up what
kind of goes where
kind of goes where
this is the arm right now.
this is the arm right now.
When I'm working on a first suit, I mainly do the sewing and assembly of the pieces.
When I'm working on a first suit, I mainly do the sewing and assembly of the pieces.
First suits are a lot different than sewing
First suits are a lot different than sewing
clothing or household items or other things.
clothing or household items or other things.
And I'm learning to use machines.
And I'm learning to use machines.
I've never used a lot more hardware that I've never installed.
I've never used a lot more hardware that I've never installed.
There's just a lot more that goes into it than I've done sewing before.
There's just a lot more that goes into it than I've done sewing before.
Working on Hero suit.
Working on Hero suit.
I've been paying a lot more attention to the detail
I've been paying a lot more attention to the detail
and trying to make sure it's exactly what he wants.
and trying to make sure it's exactly what he wants.
I hope it makes him really happy.
I hope it makes him really happy.
This is the chest. We use coil zippers so we can cut them
This is the chest. We use coil zippers so we can cut them
as long as we need.
as long as we need.
It's super satisfying to see a big table full of fluff
It's super satisfying to see a big table full of fluff
pieces come together into something that actually looks like a suit.
pieces come together into something that actually looks like a suit.
And the hum of the sewing machine is one of the most relaxing noises.
And the hum of the sewing machine is one of the most relaxing noises.
It is not very fun with thread.
It is not very fun with thread.
This is supposed to
This is supposed to
know.
know.
Yeah,
Yeah,
these things are such a
these things are such a
fiddly missed.
fiddly missed.
Your fault fails, read the man,
Your fault fails, read the man,
make sure
make sure
and about to put the claws in Hero's hand pots.
and about to put the claws in Hero's hand pots.
And these are the claws that have been pre made by James and these are resin claws.
And these are the claws that have been pre made by James and these are resin claws.
They're really cool.
They're really cool.
It's a little bit like magic to me. I don't really understand all of it.
It's a little bit like magic to me. I don't really understand all of it.
Um but there's all these little bloopers in here.
Um but there's all these little bloopers in here.
There's a knife right here that comes down and cuts the
There's a knife right here that comes down and cuts the
for and as that's being cut all the loops form these loops
for and as that's being cut all the loops form these loops
around the edge. So that's a super secure stitch. It's not going anywhere,
around the edge. So that's a super secure stitch. It's not going anywhere,
put my safety guard down. So I don't
put my safety guard down. So I don't
cut my fingers off.
cut my fingers off.
And then there's another line on the other side.
And then there's another line on the other side.
This is one of my favorite parts.
This is one of my favorite parts.
So
So
nice Hero
nice Hero
222.
222.
He was talking to me about saying, well
On a parler à propos du fait que :
if this is not made by the time I, by the time I passed away,
Si ce n'est pas terminé avant que je meurt
then we'll give it to a friend of mine. And I just like
alors je voudrais la donner à un ami à moi.
that's heavy,
C'étais intense.
that was really heavy
C'étais vraiment intense.
and it made me realize that he needs, he needs to experience what I experienced. And
Ça m'a fait comprendre qu'il devais expérimenté ce que j'ai expérimenté.
so that's,
Alors...
that's why I wanted to bring him to the front
c'est pour ça que je l'ai
of the queue and make this happen because he's just
fait passé en priorité, parce que...
Life is short and
La vie est courte,
I mean he's 24 and I'm I'm 46. Let's see.
Il a 24 ans, j'en ai 46, voyons...
You realize
Vous réalisez
life is an experience, a gift. It's a gift of experiences.
Que la vie est une expérience. Que c'est un cadeau.
It seems like something so silly.
Cette chose semble tellement idiote,
It seems like something, it's like it's, it's a mask, it's a costume,
c'est juste un masque, un costume.
but it really is something so much more than that.
Mais en réalité c'est bien plus.
And that's that's was the realization that I, I had when I, when I got to see
C'est la constatation que j'ai faite quand j'ai reçu Acai
the suit
Cette fursuit
gives him to be the best self he is.
lui permet de se sentir meilleur
But essentially, but this also represents him as the best self that he is.
mais le montre aussi comme le meilleur de ce qu'il est.
So I'm definitely, you know,
Alors, vous savez, je me donne
putting that extra energy into making this be as amazing as possible.
vraiment à fond pour rendre cette fursuit aussi incroyable que possible.
I was really touched by what Ryan offered to do.
J'ai été très touché par ce qu'à fait Ryan.
It makes me feel like we're not just making first suits.
Je me suis dis qu'on était pas juste des créateur de fursuits.
It's nice to have your work mean that much.
C'est super de faire un travail qui compte tant.
You nearly got away.
You nearly got away.
The back looks cool. It's cool to see it like so Oh wow, look at that.
L'arrière est vraiment bien, c'est bien de la voir comme ça... oh regardez !
I love this. But here's my paper
J'adore cette partie là.
really at the end of the day.
En fin de compte,
These are people that I will see at cons over and over again
ce sont des gens que je verrais tout le temps en convention
and I want to see them having fun.
et je veux les voir s'amuser.
Today is basically uh, we're going to see what all are we going to do.
Aujourd'hui, en gros, on va voir tout ce qu'il nous reste à faire.
I think we're gonna be ready to go ahead and glue for onto the head.
Je pense qu'on sera prêt à coller la fourrure sur la tête.
You gotta get the nose finished up. So I've got a pattern of the nose,
You gotta get the nose finished up. So I've got a pattern of the nose,
get the teeth installed,
Il faut coller les dents.
create a tongue
Faire une langue.
after. That will be some shaving.
Après ça, on rase un peu.
Then it's going to be the eyes
Ensuite on passe aux yeux.
airbrushing.
Airbrushing...
It's not just a business, this is a passion, this is me creating the things,
Ce n'est pas juste un business, c'est une passion, je peux créer
something that I love and something that gave me such happiness
ces choses que j'aime et qui me donne beaucoup de joie
and being able to recreate this and do this for,
et je peux le faire pour les autres.
There's a squirrel.
Il y a un écureuil.
Yeah, I got two areas
J'ai deux bâtiments
now. The
Il y a
studio here
le studio là-bas
basically,
là où
most of the assembly occurs. So
on fait l'essentiel de l'assemblage
we've got all the first storage up here at the sewing machines,
du stockage et il y a aussi nos machines à coudre.
all of that building and then I actually finished.
Tout ça dans ce bâtiment.
I don't even know what to expect when I go in there and see it for the first time.
Je ne sais pas à quoi m'attendre avant d'entrer et de la voir enfin.
I tend to bottle a lot of stuff up. I don't express myself very much.
Je suis assez réservé, je ne m'exprime pas beaucoup.
I'm hoping it just helps me be less like socially awkward and engage more with people
J'espère que ça m'aidera à être moins bizarre socialement et à aller d'avantage vers les autres.
to put a face to the animal.
Je peux enfin mettre un visage sur l'animal.
Hey, good to meet you.
Hello, content de te rencontrer.
We three d print these and then essentially
On les imprime en 3D
supply wax too.
et on utilise de la cire.
He is way outdone himself and I'm saying that now before I even see the thing.
Il s'est vraiment surpassé et je dis ça avant même d'avoir vu le résultat.
Oh man,
Ouah !
you did an incredible job with that.
Quel travail incroyable.
you did so good on this.
Tu t'es tellement bien débrouillé.
Thank you.
Merci !
Give it a try.
Essaye-la !
I want to give you a hug and
Viens me faire un câlin !
the airbrush on you, get your face. Oh, you look wonderful. This is my favorite.
the airbrush on you, get your face. Oh, you look wonderful. This is my favorite.
You're my favorite.
Tu es mon préféré.
We did it.
On l'a fait !
Honestly, it's gonna be a long time before I really know how to feel about it.
Ça va me prendre du temps de comprendre ce que je dois ressentir pour cette fursuit.
It's been
Ça a été
pretty emotional. Honestly,
assez émouvant, pour être honnête,
just seeing,
de voir,
you know,
vous savez,
something that means so much to me and something that
quelque chose qui compte tant pour moi
represents so much brought to life in that much detail
et qui représente tant, prendre vie de manière si réelle.
is just incredible.
C'est incroyable.
I still don't even know like how to process any of it.
Je ne sais toujours pas de quelle manière réagir.
Even being here.
Même d'être ici,
It's just
c'est juste...
everything changed so quickly.
Tout à changé si soudainement.
Everything happened so quickly.
Tout est arrivé si soudainement.
I want to use it for charity events.
Je veux l'utiliser pour des bonne actions.
Like I've had ideas to do it for primary Children's Hospital or for
Like I've had ideas to do it for primary Children's Hospital
Huntsman Cancer Institute where I'm going help kids make personas or something.
Huntsman Cancer Institute where I'm going help kids make personas or something.
Ultimately the goal is to just make people's days brighter.
Au final, le but est de rendre les autres heureux pour la journée.
I never expected to get diagnosed with cancer
Je ne m'étais pas attendu à être avoir un cancer, pas du tout.
You know,
c'est ce qui a fait de moi la personne que je suis
I think that if I didn't have those experiences,
et je pense que si je n'avais pas eu ces expériences
I don't think I'd be
je ne pense pas que j'aurais
as good of a person honestly. You know, I think it's kind of
été une aussi bonne personne. Je pense que
showing me how to be more
ça m'a montré comment être plus
sympathetic to people.
compatissant envers les autres.
I've learned a lot about the power of the people that you have in your lives,
J'ai beaucoup appris sur le pouvoir qu'on les gens dans notre vie,
like the impact that they can have on you and coming here
l'impact qu'ils peuvent avoir sur nous et venir ici
even has had a huge impact on me and it's made me
a aussi eu un impact significatif sur moi, ça me pousse
even want to fight it even more than I did before.
à me battre encore plus que ce que je faisais avant.
It's scary and it's not just like my family,
C'est effrayant, ce n'est pas que ma famille,
but cancer rates in the United States or even skyrocketing.
le taux de mort par cancer explose aux États-unis
And a lot of it is due to the lack of access to health care, an ambulance, right?
et une bonne partie est du à l'absence d'accès au soins. Une ambulance,
Is like,
par exemple,
it costs more than a burial,
coute plus cher qu'un enterrement.
so
Donc bon...
no one should have to choose between dying or being in debt.
On ne devrais pas choisir entre mourir et crouler sous les dettes.
If you have a positive outlook on life, it changes who you are.
Si vous avez un point de vue positif sur la vie, ça vous changera en mieux.
I want to give back to the fandom what the fandom gave me,
Je voudrais rendre aux fandom furry ce qu'il m'a donné,
which was quite possibly a second opportunity at life.
c'est à dire l'opportunité de vivre à nouveau.
I personally don't think that I'm a very memorable person.
Je ne pense pas être personne particulière,
You know, you might think otherwise,
peut-être que vous-vous dite le contraire,
but I just,
mais je...
I
veux contribuer comme je peux, j'imagine.